Hey, everyone, what's up? Have you ever wished you had a time machine?
みんな、こんにちは。タイムマシンがあったらいいなと思ったことはある？
Well, guess what? In English, you totally do.
実は、英語にはそれがあるんだ。
It's this really cool tense
それはすごく面白い時制だよ。
that lets us connect the past and the present all in one sentence.
過去と現在を一文でつなげることができるんだ。
So today, we're gonna learn how to master this time machine.
今日はこのタイムマシンをマスターしよう。
Let's get started. So just think about this for a second.
さあ始めよう。ちょっと考えてみて。
How long have you known your best friend?
あなたは親友をどれくらい知っている？
Or maybe how long have you been in your favorite after-school club?
あるいは、好きな放課後のクラブにはどれくらい参加している？
See, that all started sometime in the past, right?
それは過去のある時点から始まったよね？
But it's still true right now.
でも今もそれは真実だ。
Well, English has a special grammar just for that.
英語にはそれ専用の特別な文法があるんだ。
And that's what we're gonna dive into today. All right, first up,
今日はそれを深く掘り下げていくよ。まずは、
we're calling this the time machine tense. Why?
これをタイムマシンの時制と呼ぶよ。なぜかというと、
Because that's exactly what it does.
まさにそれを実現するから。
It lets us travel through time with our words. So, what is it really?
言葉で時間を旅することができるんだ。じゃあ、実際には何なの？
The present perfect is basically like a bridge.
現在完了形は基本的に橋のようなもの。
It connects something that happened in the past
過去に起こったことをつなげて、
all the way to this very moment to the present, you know?
今この瞬間までつなげるんだ。
If you say, I have studied English for five years,
「私は5年間英語を勉強している」と言ったら、
that have is the magic word that tells everyone you're still studying.
その「have」が魔法の言葉で、まだ勉強していることを示すんだ。
It's so powerful.
とても力強いよ。
Okay, check this out because this makes it super clear.
これを見て、すごくわかりやすいから。
Look at that top timeline. Jane stayed in London. See that little dot?
上のタイムラインを見て。ジェーンはロンドンに滞在していた。小さな点が見える？
That means it happened and it's over, finished.
それは起こったことが終わったことを示している。
But now look at the bottom one. Jane has stayed in London.
でも、下のタイムラインを見て。ジェーンはロンドンに滞在している。
You see that long bar?
長いバーが見える？
It starts in the past and goes all the way to now.
それは過去から今まで続いていることを示している。
That means she's still there. That's our time machine in action.
つまり、彼女はまだそこにいる。これがタイムマシンの動作だ。
So cool, right? So you wanna build this awesome machine.
すごいよね？この素晴らしい機械を作りたい？
It's way easier than you think.
思っているよりずっと簡単だよ。
Let's take a look at the basic blueprint. It's just three easy steps.
基本的な設計図を見てみよう。たったの3つの簡単なステップだ。
That's it. First, you need your subject.
まずは主語が必要だ。
You know, I, you, he, she, that kind of thing.
「私」「あなた」「彼」「彼女」みたいなもの。
Step two, add the magic engine words, have or has.
次に、魔法のエンジンの言葉「have」または「has」を追加する。
Just remember to use has for he, she, or it.
「he」「she」「it」には「has」を使うことを忘れないで。
And finally, step three, add the past participle,
最後に、過去分詞を追加する。
which is that third form of the verb, like known, lived, or been.
それは動詞の3つ目の形、例えば「known」「lived」「been」など。
Subject, have or has, past participle. Boom, you've built it.
主語、haveまたはhas、過去分詞。これで完成だ。
Okay, every cool machine needs fuel to run, right?
さて、すべての素晴らしい機械には燃料が必要だよね？
Well, our time machine is no different.
私たちのタイムマシンも同じだ。
To tell people exactly how long something's been going on,
何かがどれくらい続いているかを正確に伝えるために、
we've got two special kinds of fuel, four and cents.
「for」と「since」という2つの特別な燃料がある。
Now getting these two right is super important,
この2つを正しく使うことがとても重要だよ。
but it's easy once you get the hang of it. Think of it this way.
でも、慣れれば簡単だよ。こう考えてみて。
You use four when you're talking about a length of time,
「for」は時間の長さについて話すときに使う。
like a duration, you know, for three years, for two hours.
例えば「3年間」「2時間」のように。
But you use since when you're talking about the starting point.
でも「since」は始まりの時点について話すときに使う。
It's like circling a date on your calendar,
カレンダーの日付を丸で囲むようなものだよ。
since 2020, since this morning. So four is the amount of time,
「2020年から」「今朝から」のように。「for」は時間の量、
and since is when it all began. All right, pop quiz time.
「since」は始まりの時点を示す。さて、クイズの時間だ。
Let's see if you've been paying attention. Take a look at the screen.
あなたが注意を払っていたか見てみよう。画面を見て。
You gotta fill in two blanks in that sentence. What do you think?
その文の2つの空欄を埋めてみて。どう思う？
I'll give you a second.
少し考える時間をあげるよ。
And the answer is I have known him since he was a child.
答えは「私は彼を子供の頃から知っている」だよ。
We need known because that's the past participle.
「known」が必要なのは過去分詞だから。
And we use since because when he was a child
「since」を使うのは「彼が子供の頃」が
is the specific starting point. Awesome job.
特定の始まりの時点だからだ。素晴らしい仕事だね。
Okay, you've built the machine. You've got the fuel.
さて、機械を作った。燃料もある。
Now it's time to get in the pilot's seat.
今度は操縦席に座る時間だ。
Let's figure out how to ask questions
質問の仕方を考えてみよう。
so you can learn about other people's own time travel adventures.
他の人のタイムトラベルの冒険について学べます。
Asking questions is super easy.
質問するのはとても簡単です。
If you wanna ask a simple yes or no question,
はいかいいえで答えられる質問をしたいなら、
just take have or has and pop it right at the front.
haveまたはhasを文の最初に置くだけです。
Like, have you known her for a long time? And the answer is easy too.
例えば、「あなたは彼女を長い間知っていますか？」という感じです。 答えも簡単です。
Yes I have or no I haven't. But if you really wanna know the details,
「はい、知っています」または「いいえ、知りません」と。詳細を知りたいなら、
you start with those magic words, how long?
魔法の言葉「どのくらい」を使います。
Okay pilots, here's another challenge for you.
さあ、パイロットの皆さん、もう一つの挑戦です。
Put these words in the right order to make a question.
これらの言葉を正しい順序に並べて質問を作ってください。
How would you ask someone
誰かに
about how long they've been studying Spanish. Go for it. Nailed it.
スペイン語をどのくらい勉強しているかを尋ねるにはどうしますか？やってみてください。
How long have you studied Spanish? You got it.
「どのくらいスペイン語を勉強していますか？」正解です。
You start with how long, and then the question part. Have you studied?
「どのくらい」で始めて、次に質問部分です。「勉強していますか？」
Fantastic. You are now officially ready to pilot your time machine.
素晴らしい。これでタイムマシンを操縦する準備が整いました。
All right, you've got your pilot's license.
さあ、パイロットライセンスを手に入れました。
So let's take this time machine for a spin.
では、このタイムマシンを試してみましょう。
We're gonna check out a quick story
短い物語を見てみます。
about a girl named Yumi and her friend Ken.
ユミという女の子と彼女の友達ケンについてです。
Pay attention to how they use the present perfect. So here's Yumi.
彼らが現在完了形をどう使っているかに注目してください。ユミがこう言います。
She says, I have lived here since 2010. See that?
「私は2010年からここに住んでいます。」見えますか？
The starting point was 2010, and she's still living there right now.
始まりは2010年で、今もそこに住んでいます。
A perfect link between the past and the present.
過去と現在をつなぐ完璧なリンクです。
And here she talks about her best friend Ken.
そして、彼女は親友のケンについて話します。
I have known him for five years. This time, she uses four
「私は彼を5年間知っています。」今回は期間について話しているので、
because she's talking about the duration, right?
「4」を使っていますよね？
The whole period of their friendship. Now, check this one out.
彼らの友情の全期間についてです。さあ、これを見てください。
Ken has had a dog since last month. Notice how it's has had?
ケンは先月から犬を飼っています。「has had」に注目してください。
That's because Ken is a he, so we use has.
ケンは男性なので「has」を使います。
And when did he get the dog? Last month, that's the starting point.
彼はいつ犬を飼い始めたのか？先月、それが始まりです。
Oh no, poor Ken. It says he has been sick since yesterday.
ああ、かわいそうなケン。彼は昨日から病気だそうです。
So again, we use has for Ken,
だから、ケンには「has」を使います。
and since tells us his sickness started yesterday
「since」は彼の病気が昨日始まったことを示しています。
and he's still sick today.
そして、彼は今日もまだ病気です。
And finally, Yumi says, I haven't seen him since then.
最後に、ユミは「私はそれ以来彼に会っていません」と言います。
This is a perfect example of the negative. have not becomes haven't.
これは否定形の完璧な例です。「have not」は「haven't」になります。
So from yesterday until right now, she hasn't seen him.
昨日から今まで、彼女は彼に会っていません。
I really hope he gets better soon. Wow, what a trip.
彼が早く良くなることを本当に願っています。すごい旅でした。
You learned how to build the time machine,
タイムマシンの作り方を学び、
how to fuel it, and you even took it for a test drive.
燃料の入れ方も知り、試運転もしました。
So let's do a super quick review of the controls
では、あなたの新しい英語のスーパーパワーの
for your new English superpower.
コントロールを超簡単に復習しましょう。
All right, let's look at your time machine's dashboard one last time.
さあ、タイムマシンのダッシュボードを最後に見てみましょう。
The formula is your engine. Have or has, plus the past participle.
公式はエンジンです。「have」または「has」、プラス過去分詞です。
It's whole purpose to connect the past to right now.
その目的は過去と今をつなぐことです。
Your fuel is for to talk about a period of time
燃料は時間の期間について話すため、
and sense to talk about a starting point.
「since」は始まりのポイントについて話すためです。
And of course to ask questions,
もちろん、質問をするには、
you just start with have, has or how long. You got this.
「have」「has」または「how long」で始めれば大丈夫です。
And hey, before we go, I really want you to remember this.
さて、行く前にこれを覚えておいてほしいです。
This grammar stuff, it's not just about passing a test.
この文法のことは、テストに合格するためだけではありません。
It's a real tool.
本当のツールです。
It's how you tell people about the friends you've had
あなたが長年持っている友達や、
for years or the hobbies you've loved since you were a kid.
子供の頃から好きだった趣味について話す方法です。
It's all about telling your story.
自分の物語を語ることが大切です。
So my last question is for you, and I really want you to think about it.
最後の質問はあなたへのものです。よく考えてほしいです。
What is something that you have loved since you were a child?
子供の頃から好きなものは何ですか？
An anime? A sport? A video game? See?
アニメ？スポーツ？ビデオゲーム？そうですか？
Now you have the perfect way to answer that in English.
今、英語でその答えを完璧に言う方法があります。
Thanks so much for hanging out and learning with me today.
今日は一緒に学んでくれてありがとう。